<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debabrata Choudhury</title>
    <description>A Hardcore Nix user</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 07:29:43 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 07:29:43 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>End Of 32Bit Support in Arch Linux</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Arch Linux developer Bartłomiej Piotrowski is announcing the upcoming deprecation of 32-bit (i686) support from the official ISO image of the popular rolling release operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, it’s only a draft message on their [arch-dev-public][dev-post] mailing list, but it will soon be published on the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;Arch Linux website&lt;/a&gt; for all users, and it means that the forthcoming February 1, 2017 release of Arch Linux will be the last one provided as a dual-arch ISO image, for both 64- and 32-bit hardware platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with the March 1, 2017 release, the official &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.softpedia.com/news/arch-linux-gets-first-iso-respin-for-2017-still-powered-by-linux-kernel-4-8-13-511526.shtml&quot;&gt;Arch Linux ISO&lt;/a&gt; won’t be a dual-arch one, but only a 64-bit image, which means that you won’t be able to install the operating system on a 32-bit computer, if you still have one of those around. However, 32-bit support for existing systems is not going away anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Due to the decreasing popularity of i686 among the developers and the community, we have decided to phase out the support of this architecture,” said Bartłomiej Piotrowski. “The decision means that February ISO will be the last that allows to install 32-bit Arch Linux. The next 9 months are deprecation period, during which i686 will be still receiving upgraded packages.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Unofficial 32-bit ISOs of Arch Linux could be provided by the community”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no need to panic if you’re using &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.softpedia.com/news/arch-anywhere-iso-lets-you-install-a-fully-custom-arch-linux-system-in-minutes-512082.shtml&quot;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt; on a 32-bit system, because package updates will be provided for you through the official channels, until the end of October 2017. From November 2017 onwards, i686 support is becoming obsolete, but there’s a chance that the community can keep 32-bit support alive for a longer period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those interested in keeping 32-bit support alive are encouraged to contact the Arch Linux developers through the official channels, and with their guidance, it might still be possible to install the operating system on a 32-bit machine.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 07:34:23 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//linux/2017/05/18/end-of-32bit-support.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//linux/2017/05/18/end-of-32bit-support.html</guid>
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why We use Linux</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We tell people we use Linux because it’s secure. Or because it’s free, because it’s customizable, because it has excellent community support…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all of that is just marketing bullshit. We tell that to non-Linuxers because they wouldn’t understand the real reason. And when we say those false reasons enough, we might even start to believe them ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But deep underneath, the real reason remains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use Linux because it’s fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s fun to tinker with your system. It’s fun to change all the settings, break the system, then have to go to recovery mode to repair it. It’s fun to have over a hundred distros to choose from. It’s fun to use the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me say that again. It’s fun to use the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No wonder non-Linuxers wouldn’t understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point with us Linux fans is – we use Linux for its own sake. Sure, we like to get work done. Sure, we like to be secure from viruses. Sure, we like to save money. But those are only the side-effects. What we really like is playing with the system, poking around, and discovering completely pointless yet fascinating facts about the OS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three main reasons Linux is so much fun:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linux gives you complete control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever tried stopping a process in Windows and the OS wouldn’t let you? Ever tried deleting a file – and you couldn’t? Even though you had admin rights?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux lets you do anything. That’s the great benefit of usually logging in as user. If you login as the root, the OS assumes you know what you’re doing. Once you become root, everything is allowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linux isn’t widely used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a paradox. We often complain Linux isn’t more widely used. But that’s one of the reasons we use it. It gives us a feeling of being a special clique. Like we’re better than “those ignorant masses”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Linux becomes widely used, we’ll probably switch to something else. Or at least develop an obscure distro that only we will use. Because, let’s face it, we want to feel special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linux is free (as-in-speech)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can get the source code for all our applications. If we want to know how a certain part of the OS works, we can. This lets us tweak and play with our systems. And we absolutely loo-o-o-ve tweaking our system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course we can’t tell non-Linuxers we use Linux because it’s fun – they’d stick us into a mental asylum quicker than you can say “antidisestablishmentarianism”. So we’ll keep telling them the false yet plausible reasons for using Linux. But deep inside, we’ll know the real reason we use Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And maybe, just maybe, next time someone asks me why I use Linux, I’ll flash a huge smile and answer: “Because using Linux is FUN!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Reason for Using Linux&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 06:34:23 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//linux/2017/05/12/why-we-use-linux.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//linux/2017/05/12/why-we-use-linux.html</guid>
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
